# Reuben Bagtas

# WEB DEVELOPER · SERVICE-FOCUSED · COMPLEX PROBLEM SOLVER

🏷 (+1) 310-946-1111 | 🔼 ReubenBagtas@gmail.com | 🗋 www.ReubenBagtas.com

#### Summary

Service-focused Web Developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including Javascript, HTML and SQL. Strong background in customer relations and management.

### **Projects**

YumYack Full Stack Developer

- Social media website where clients can upload and share exotic foods to friends.
- Website functionalities includes user comments, rating system and notifications.
- Utilized Yelp API to redirect users to Yelp and display the nearest restaurants that serves the highlighted food.
- Developed front end in **Angular**, paired with **Sass** CSS preprocessor and **Bootstrap**.
- Secured clients information using **Bcrypt**, and stored user data using **MongoDb**.
- Deployed server in AWS ec2.

LitNerd App Developer

- Comic book iOS App that lets users search and save comic books.
- Developed in Swift and Xcode.
- Utilized cloud services such as AWS Gateway, AWS lamdba and AWS DynamoDb.
- Deployed in the **App Store**.

#### Skills

LANGUAGES	FRAMEWORKS	DATABASES	OTHER
<ul> <li>HTML</li> <li>CSS</li> <li>Python</li> <li>Java</li> <li>Javascript</li> <li>Swift</li> <li>SQL</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Django</li> <li>Flask</li> <li>Angular 4</li> <li>Express.js</li> <li>Node.js</li> <li>Bootstrap</li> </ul>	<ul><li>MySQL</li><li>MongoDB</li><li>AWS DynamoDB</li></ul>	<ul> <li>Tagalog</li> <li>Linux</li> <li>AWS Lambda</li> <li>AWS Gateway</li> <li>AWS Ec2</li> </ul>

#### Work Experience

# Freelance Web Developer

Remote

Self Employed

June 2017 - Present

- Efficiently and reliably completed websites for clients from single clients to small businesses using frameworks such as Bootstrap, Angular, and Django.
- Implemented open source server framework using **Node.js**, implemented creating API using **Express**.

### **Technology Sales Specialist**

Seal Beach, Ca

Marketsource

Coding Dojo

Aug. 2017-Present

June. 2017-Aug. 2017

- Demonstrate, market, sell and advertise products.
- Drive product sales at assigned events through customer interaction.
- **Top salesman** in the Orange County district for the month of November.

### **Teaching Assistant**

Burbank, Ca

Lead classroom instruction by delivering lectures and answering questions.

- Administer and grade assessments to evaluate student progress.
- Report to Bootcamp Instructor and communicate student progress data.
- Provide live coding demos to help simplify complex web development concepts.

### Education

# **Coding Dojo**

Mar. 2017 - Aug 2017

Full Stack Developer Program

### California State University, Long Beach

Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy, Value Theory

Aug 2010 - May 2013